(train chugging)
(train whistle blows)
ADULT SHELDON:
I've always loved trains.
In fact, if my career
in theoretical physics hadn't
worked out, my backup plan
was to become
a professional ticket taker.
Or hobo.
(train whistle blows)
♪ ♪
And when I figured out
that trains allowed me
to prove Newton's first law--
an object in motion stays
in motion
with the same speed
and in the same direction
unless acted upon
by an unbalanced force--
I felt like Neil Armstrong
on the moon,
alone and happy.
MARY:
Shelly, dinner's ready!
♪ Be-bop-a-lula,
baby, what I say ♪
(giggles) I don't care
how dimwitted you are.
Scientific principles
have to make you smile.
Of course,
nobody I knew in East Texas
in 1989 cared
about Newtonian physics.
The only Newtons
they cared about
were Wayne and Fig.
MISSY: Sheldon, if
you don't get in here,
I'm gonna lick
your toothbrush!
Coming!
That's my sister.
And she's done it before.
♪ Do the walk of life ♪
♪ Yeah, he do
the walk of life. ♪
The hell
were you doing
out there?
George,
language.
What language? So?
I was exploring dimensional kinematics.
Admit it--
he's adopted.
SHELDON:
How can I be adopted
when I have a twin sister?
Think, monkey, think.
MARY:
That's enough.
No one's adopted.
I wish I was.
That can still be arranged.
Now, let's pray.
A moment, please.
(sighs)
Leave him be.
He can hold hands
with his family.
It won't kill him.
We don't know that.
Georgie, did you wash
your hands before dinner?
Or even this week?
None of your business.
Hence the mittens.
MARY: Thank you, God,
for this food
we're about to receive and for
the nourishment of our bodies,
and bless the hands
that prepared it.
ALL:
Amen.
How come we ain't got
no tater tots?
I made tater tots last night.
GEORGE: I'd take
tater tots
over mashed potaters any day.
Just eat what I made you.
Can we at least
have tater tots
tomorrow?
ADULT SHELDON:
It was family dinners like this
that led me to adopt
a mid-Atlantic accent.
Nobel Prize winners...
(Southern accent):
ought not be orderin'
tater tots.
Everybody excited
to start school Monday?
I am.
I guess so.
MARY:
Georgie?
Freshman year,
that's a big deal.
How can I be excited
when he's gonna be
in the same grade as me?
SHELDON:
Don't worry, Georgie,
I'm not planning
on being in the ninth
grade for very long.
All I know is he's not in
the same grade as me anymore,
and I'm thrilled.
Good luck
with your finger painting.
You're gonna get your ass kicked
in high school.
MARY:
Hey, language.
I'm not going to be assaulted.
High school is a haven
for higher learning.
Oh, dear God.
Speaking of God,
who's going to church
with me tomorrow?
GEORGE SR.: I can't.
I'm meeting
with the other coaches.
You can't meet after church?
No, Mary,
I can't meet after church.
Georgie?
I got to study
my playbook.
I'll go with you, Mom.
MISSY:
Why are you going?
You don't believe in God.
No,
but I believe in Mom.
I'll take it. Missy?
Can't, Heather
asked me to...
You're goin'.
Son of a bitch.
Hey.
Ow!
(laughs)
MARY: Missy...
(gasps) Don't you
throw something at the
dinner table. George Jr.
ADULT SHELDON:
Jane Goodall had to go
to Africa to study apes.
MISSY:
Hey!
I just had to go to dinner.
Never at the
dinner table!
You knock that
off, George!
D-Do not retaliate!
ALL:
♪ Onward, Christian soldiers ♪
♪ Marching as to war ♪
♪ With the cross of Jesus ♪
♪ Going on before. ♪
In Matthew nine, verse four,
Jesus said,
"Why would you entertain
evil thoughts in your hearts?"
(quietly):
Do you have evil thoughts?
Shh.
I just don't think
this part applies to me.
That's fine.
Be quiet and listen.
I'm only nine years old.
Most evil doesn't start
till puberty.
(clears throat)
Hello.
Philippians 4:8,
"Finally, brothers,
whatever is..."
Do you have
evil thoughts?
I'm having one
right now.
Really? What is it?
When we get home, I'm gonna
kick your little balls.
You can't.
They haven't descended yet.
Mom?
What?
When should I be expecting
my testicles?
"...whatever
is admirable..."
What is wrong with him?
Nothin' is wrong with him.
Now, turn around before
I knock your lights out.
PASTOR: ...think continually
on these things.
A good thought
leads
to a good thing.
You feel it in your body.
You feel it in your...
ADULT SHELDON: My mom was
my Christian soldier.
...leads to evil things
and sits there and...
And for the record,
they descended when I was 15.
(whirring)
♪ ♪
Shelly, it's your last day
of summer. Go out and enjoy it.
But I have to learn
the student handbook.
Ooh, did you know
extreme hairstyles,
goatees and mustaches
are not allowed?
I didn't.
I personally find
that very reassuring.
Look what a beautiful day it is.
(loud whirring)
(tires screeching)
(deep barking)
Go play.
"Go play"-- if only
life were that simple.
There, I played.
Hey, Sheldon!
Hello, Billy Sparks.
Hello, Matilda Sparks.
I heard
you're going
to high school tomorrow.
I am.
You're going to have
to find someone else
to torment on the playground.
"Torment"?
(sighs)
It means to maliciously harass.
"Her ass"?
(chuckles)
That's funny.
Well, this was nice.
Hey, doofus!
(squawks)
Mom!
Good girl.
MARY: What am I supposed to do?
His feet are growing.
GEORGE SR.: Why can't
he wear Georgie's old shoes?
MARY: He won't
hold your hand.
You think he's gonna put his feet
in his brother's smelly shoes?
GEORGE SR.: Well, we damn well
better cut back somewhere.
MARY: Will you please keep
your voice down?
(door shuts)
They're fighting
about you again.
They're fighting about money.
It's a common argument
in marriages.
(door opens)
Lights out.
Big day tomorrow.
Mom?
Hmm?
Do we have financial problems?
Don't you worry about that.
We are fine.
Now, go to sleep.
(sighs)
She's lying. She just said that
to make you feel better.
Mom doesn't lie.
Sure, she thinks
the Earth was made in six days,
but that's 'cause
she's gullible, not a liar.
MISSY:
Mom,
Sheldon can't find his bowtie.
Really? I laid it out for him.
Leave it alone, Mary.
He doesn't need a bowtie.
It's his first day of school.
Let him wear what he wants.
SHELDON:
Mom, I can't
find my bowtie!
Dear Lord, why's he
got to wear a bowtie?
Can I drive in with you?
Sure.
Everybody's gonna know
he's your brother.
It's gonna be awful for you.
Tell her to shut up.
She's not wrong.
(TV plays quietly)
It's got to be here.
SHELDON:
It's not.
It's not!
Shelly, stay calm.
We'll find it.
My tie is gone!
Shelly,
you don't really need a tie.
I have to find my tie.
Be right back.
Professor Proton wears a bowtie!
George Junior,
give me back that
bowtie right now!
I didn't take it!
Don't you lie to me!
I'm not lying!
We'll see about that.
Stay out of my room!
She's gonna find
your dirty magazines.
Shut up!
You are not having a good day.
(sighs)
Ugh!
Hey. Hey,
he didn't take it.
Then what
happened to it?!
SHELDON:
Help me find my bowtie!
I'll check in
the bathroom!
I took it.
Why would you do that?
Mary,
the boy is nine years old
and going into high school.
Isn't that weird enough?
Give it to me.
Come on.
It's not just Sheldon.
Georgie's gonna be
in class with him.
Not in the bathroom!
Give it.
♪ Think about it ♪
♪ There must be higher love ♪
♪ Down in the heart
or hidden in the stars above ♪
♪ Without it... ♪
Would you like
to play a driving game?
Not really. I always lose.
I know. That's why it's fun.
(laughs)
How about license plates
with prime numbers
followed by
a cons...?
Why don't we just talk?
Very well.
You understand
that some people are gonna be
intimidated by you
'cause of how smart you are?
Or maybe
they'll recognize my intellect
and make me their leader.
Lord, look after my son.
Don't let him get
stuffed in a gym bag.
♪ Bring me a higher love,
oh, oh ♪
♪ Bring me a higher love... ♪
(distorted sounds
and voices)
(distorted speech)
Oh, dear.
Yeah.
That boy has
an exposed tattoo.
He does.
I wonder if he knows
that's in violation
of the dress code.
Speaking of which, how
about we lose the bowtie?
Why?
Look around, honey. None of the
other kids are wearing one.
Well, perhaps I'll start a fad.
No, you won't.
Please trust Mommy.
All right,
tell you what.
You take it off,
and this weekend,
I'll take you to RadioShack.
Hmm?
(bell ringing)
(indistinct chatter)
(growling)
You doing okay?
I guess.
(roars)
I smell ammonia.
They must've done
a thorough cleaning recently.
I like that.
MARY: And remember, if anybody
bothers you, what do you say?
My dad's a football coach.
And?
My brother's a football player.
Good.
Hey, Mom, look.
That girl's pregnant.
Congratulations.
(toilet flushing)
Well, that was revolting.
All right.
This is your homeroom.
Do you want me
to go in with you?
No. Although I could've used you
in the restroom.
Okay, well...
You have a good day.
And I'll pick you up
after school,
same door we came in.
Are you crying or having
an allergy attack?
Allergies.
It's probably the ammonia.
Probably.
(sniffles)
Okay. Let the learning begin.
(exhales)
All right, everybody,
my name is Ms. MacElroy.
In addition to being
your homeroom teacher,
I'll be seeing some of you
in my English class,
and some of you
on the volleyball court.
Just to give you
a little history,
I've been here at Medford
for 29 years...
(mouthing)
...I taught some of your
older brothers and sisters,
and sadly,
some of your parents.
Not much I haven't seen.
Until today.
I'm sure you're well aware
we have a student with us,
who, despite his young age,
is remarkably gifted.
And I expect y'all
to make him feel welcome.
Yes, Sheldon?
Per the student dress
and grooming code,
this boy's hair is too long,
this boy is wearing
sports attire
outside
of a designated area
and this girl's blouse
is diaphanous,
which means
I can see her brassiere.
(laughter)
Thank you.
I will take that
into account.
All right.
We have a few minutes
before first period.
I need y'all
to fill out these forms.
What?
Also in violation of the
grooming code on page 48,
article five, subsection B,
you have a bit of a mustache.
(laughter)
This is a stupid idea.
This boy does not
belong in our school.
PETERSEN: Come on Vicky,
it's just the first day.
Why don't we all just take
a deep breath here?
The hell with that. Five
minutes into my math class,
he questioned my credentials.
How am I supposed to control a
classroom when a kid accuses me
of being in breach
of the hygiene code?
Well, Hubert, it wouldn't
kill you to shower
a little more often. George,
you want to weigh in here?
Well...
INGRAM:
Oral Roberts University
is a wonderful school.
He said I was intimidated
by his intelligence,
and then,
he offered to be my "leader."
(clears throat)
(playing Mozart's Sonata in D)
(piano playing)
(stops playing)
Do you know
this sonata?
No.
How long have you
played the piano?
I don't play piano.
PETERSEN:
George,
you got any thoughts here?
I certainly do.
Mary, tell him.
It's simple.
We don't have a choice.
Well, you gave it a shot.
We wish you luck
with Sheldon elsewhere...
MARY:
No, no, no.
We don't have a choice.
He's got to stay here.
We can't afford
private school.
I sure can't
homeschool him.
He's doing calculus and
Euclidean something or other.
Euclidean geometry.
Guess where I learned that.
Yeah, yeah, we know.
All I care about
is that
my son gets the education
he deserves, so you all
are gonna have to
figure this out.
Coach, can you help me out here,
please?
'Cause I'm dyin'.
I'd rather not.
G minor.
F.
E flat.
C minor.
You have perfect pitch.
Okay.
Sweetheart, you should
really pursue music.
No, thank you.
Musicians take drugs.
Is there a faculty
restroom I could use?
(whistle blows)
♪ Ooh... ♪
(grunting)
Cooper, Stinson, you're up.
(laughs) Hey, look,
it's the dumb brother.
Okay.
(blows whistle)
(grunting, yelling)
(whistle blowing)
BERGDOFF:
That's enough. Hey.
(yelling)
(whistle blowing)
BERGDOFF:
Hey, that's enough!
Hey, hey!
GEORGE SR.:
That's enough!
Georgie.
Georgie! Georgie!
Stop! Stop!
What the hell
is wrong with you?
You okay?
No, I'm not okay.
Where you think you're going?
I quit. I don't want
to play anymore!
Since when?
Since right now!
All right, what is going on?
What do you think's going on?!
You mean Sheldon?
You can't let that bother you.
It doesn't bother you?
You got called
to the principal's office.
Yeah, that wasn't so great.
I can't be in the same school
as him!
Well, I don't see
what choice you have.
Right. Ever since he could talk,
I quit having any choices.
(groans)
I know it's hard.
I'm telling you, as your coach,
quit your whining,
get your uniform on and you
get your ass back out there.
But what about as my dad?
Your dad is
having a bad day.
Listen to your coach.
Can a clock be powered
by an ordinary potato?
I hope so, boys and girls,
or this is going to be
a really boring episode.
The supplies you'll need...
Why can't we
watch DuckTales?
'Cause we don't learn anything
watching DuckTales.
It's TV; we aren't
supposed to learn.
...two alligator grips
and, let's see...
Of course, a clock.
Missy, go somewhere else.
I need to talk to your brother.
Why don't you go somewhere else
and I can watch Duck...
Go!
I hate everybody.
It's time for science.
Hey, he was about to power
a clock with a potato.
Not possible.
Now, listen...
Am I in trouble?
No.
Maybe. Just listen.
You're not gonna
make it in this school
if you keep ratting
people out.
But they were breaking
the grooming codes
and the dress codes.
I saw one boy with a T-shirt
that said...
(whispering):
"Bite me."
Yeah. That-that's terrible.
Sheldon, let me tell
you a little story.
Did you ever wonder why we moved
from Galveston to Medford?
No. I tend to wonder
about the bigger questions.
Okay, well, here's why.
Your dad had a real good
coaching job
and I saw some grown-ups
breaking rules.
What'd they do?
I-It's kind of complicated,
but...
football coaches aren't allowed
to recruit kids
from other high schools
to play on their teams.
And you told on them?
Yeah. You know what happened?
Justice descended
upon the rule breakers?
I got fired, Sheldon.
And I got a bad
reputation.
Oh. That's why you
drink so much beer.
Just do yourself a favor.
Okay? Go to
school tomorrow,
and mind your own business.
All right?
Dad.
Are you sad that you got fired?
Mostly angry.
But yeah.
Maybe a little sad.
ReEncoded By Dr.XJ | PSA
www.PSArips.com
All right, let's say grace.
Thank you, God,
for this food we are
about to receive.
(muffled praying continues)
ADULT SHELDON:
That was the first time
I held my father's hand.
MARY: ...our bodies and bless
the hands that prepared it.
Amen.
GEORGIE: Amen.
MARY: Hey, George Jr.,
wait your turn.
ADULT SHELDON: I wouldn't
touch my brother's hand
until 17 years later,
thanks to the invention
of Purell.
You know what I find comforting?
What's that, baby?
In a world filled
with uncertainty,
this place will be here forever.
CLERK: Hey, Sheldon,
how you doing?