Previously on
Young Sheldon...
Why do you always take
his side?
I hate this family!
I was handling it till you came
and bulldozed right over me.
MARY: Sheldon was upset.GEORGE SR.:
This isn't about Sheldon.
It's about you thinking
you're always right.
Where are you going?I'm running away.
I'm coming with you.
You really want to
start this up again?
Oh, really?
Did I want to spend my evening
getting yelled at by my daughter
and my son and my wife?
I'm sorry, I didn't realize
you were so unhappy.
Because you
never bothered to ask.
BRENDA:
Hi, George.
Oh, hey, Brenda.
You want some company?
Sure.
[upbeat country music playing]
And then Missy starts tearing
everybody a new one,
'cause her little boyfriend
broke up with her.
Poor thing.
But good training for when
her husband dumps her one day.
[chuckles]
I'm sorry about that.
No, you know what, the truth is,
it was over a while ago.
It happens.But, hey,
he's got the kids tonight
and ladies drink half price,
so let's pretend I'm a lady.[laughs]
Yes, ma'am.
Mm.
You look like you could use
a shot with that beer.
Shots?
I got school in the morning.
Oh. I didn't realize we were
both here for ladies' night.
Can we get some
shots over here?
How am I supposed to compete
with a seventh grader?
Mom won't even let me shave
my legs.
Can we please go home?
You can. I'm not.
As we've established,
woods: very scary,
me: very scared.
Then I guess you're here
until the sun comes up.
So I'll be able to see
what kills me? Pass.
Can you at least go back
to complaining about boys
so I can get some sleep?
We licked the same
Ring Pop once.
It's like it
meant nothing.
[laughs]:
You were a cheerleader?
Yeah. I mean, you wouldn't
know it to look at me now.
Don't say that.
I can totally see you
on top of that pyramid.
Oh, I was on the bottom,
and you know it.
But at least
I could fill out a sweater.
You and me both, sister.
["What's Your Name"
by Lynyrd Skynyrd playing]
Oh!
I love Skynyrd!
You know what?
I saw them play Dallas.
You're kidding. Wh-What year?
I'd just got kicked out
of beauty school,
so I guess... [sighs]
'76?
I was at that show!
Stop it.Nah.
Nazareth opened.
Oh, my God. They did.
They did.
Small world.
Yeah.
♪ Shootin' you straight
♪ Little girl...
You want to dance?
[chuckles]:
Me? No.
Oh, come on.No.
There's people here.
Well...
then what if we go
someplace else?
What do you have in mind?
Herschel does have the kids.
♪ Ah, yeah...
Oh, God, I'm sorry.
[laughs]: That was...
that was over the line.
[low groan]
[pants]You okay?
George?
[exhales]
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain
♪ I bet I could be your hero
♪ I am a mighty little man
♪ I am a mighty little man.♪
ReEncoded By Dr.XJ | PSA
www.PSArips.com
Hello?
Mary, it's Brenda.
George is in the hospital.
Wha...? Why? What's going on?
I'm not sure. The paramedics
think it might be his heart.
Is he okay?
I don't know.
The doctors are with him now.
Uh...
all right, I'll be there
as soon as I can. Bye.
Georgie?
Kids, put your clothes on! We...
[Mary gasps]
And now I'm gonna need
a new notebook, 'cause mine has
"Missy and Marcus forever"
written all over it.
[snoring softly]
[people shouting on TV]
Geez. Less monkey, more Clint.
There we go.
[phone rings]
Hello?
Are the kids with you?
No. Why?
George is in the hospital,
and the kids are missing.
What's wrong with George?
Something with his heart.
I don't know what to do.
Okay, okay, uh, well,
you go to the hospital,
and I'll go over to the house
and see if I can find the kids.
Thank you.
Uh, you think
they might be with Georgie?
I don't know where he is,
either!
[rock music playing]
You sure your boss
isn't gonna show up?
Yeah, but not positive.
So let's keep this train
on the tracks.
[pager beeping, vibrating]
Aren't you gonna check that?
Nope.
But what if it's an emergency?
It's not.
I'm turning this off.
Dadgummit!
Well, is he gonna be okay?
You know as much as I do.
Now help me find the kids.
I'm on it.
I have an idea where they went.
Great. And where are you,
by the way?
Uh, at work.
This time of night? Why?
Got to find the kids.
Brenda.
Have you heard
anything?
Not yet.
Oh, what happened?
Um, I-I ran into George
at the bar,
and... next thing I know,
he started having chest pains.
Well, thank the Lord
you were there with him.
Oh. I really didn't do anything.
Don't say that!
Who knows what
would've happened
if you hadn't
been there?
[chuckles]:
Yeah.
GEORGE JR. [calls]:
Missy?
Sheldon!
[gasps]
What the hell?!
You scared me.
Everyone scared me.
Dad's in the hospital.
We got to go.
Is he okay?
I don't know.
Come on.
KWOK:
Mrs. Cooper?
Your husband's gonna be okay.
Oh! Praise the Lord.
It was
mild angina pectoris.
We're gonna keep him
for observation,
but he's awake
and you could see him now.
Thank you, Doctor.
Yeah, um...
Yeah, I'm gonna get out of here.
You go see George.
What? No!
You might have saved
his life.
He's gonna want
to thank you.
You know, that's nice,
but I think it's best if...Brenda,
I insist.
Okay.Okay.
Come on.
[monitor beeping steadily]
Hi.
Hey.
Look who I have with me.
Hey, George.
Brenda.
Are you okay?
Do you need
a doctor?
Oh, no.
Nah, I was just...
excited to see you, hmm?
[monitor beeping faster]
[rapid beeping]
[alarm beeping][nervous chuckle]
Hey.
Good news. Your
dad's doing okay
and should be home
in a couple of days.
Thank God.
Thank modern medicine.
Hmm, all right,
you two try and get
some sleep, okay?
Meemaw?
Do you think
I gave Dad a heart attack?
What?
No.
This isn't your fault.
I was really mean to him.
I was mean to him as well.
What I did was so much worse.
That is true. When
we're receiving our punishment,
they should really
let you have it.
Okay, y'all go to sleep.But I was just
an accomplice.
It wouldn't be fair
if we got equal punishment.
Sleep.
[Missy sighs]
ADULT SHELDON:
My meemaw didn't understand.
When I was feeling anxious,
it was rules and structure
that I found soothing--
not to mention
the relaxing melody
of theStar Trek theme song.
[humming Star Trektheme]
[continues humming]
Stop that.
As soon as I'm soothed.
[resumes humming
Star Trektheme]
[Sheldon hums ascending notes
ending theme]
GEORGE SR.:
Bad enough
they rolled me out
in a wheelchair I didn't need.
You could've let me drive.
You got winded
getting in the car.
You heard that, huh?
[exhales]
Should we talk about what
happened the other night?
What happened the other night?
Us having that huge fight.
Oh, that, that.
Forget it.
[scoffs]
How can I?
It was a bad night.
I say best thing is to put it
in the rearview mirror.
[sighs]:
Oh, I would love that.
Done. The other night
never happened.
Thank you.
[chuckles softly]
[sighs]
DISC JOCKEY:
And up next we've got a twofer
of Lynyrd Skynyrd coming at you.
["What's Your Name" playing]
[clicks off radio]
[chuckles] Could use
a little peace and quiet.
ADULT SHELDON:
With my father home
from the hospital,
my mother had instructed us
to let him relax.
And what could be more relaxing
than a spirited discussion
of societal rules and morality?
SHELDON:
Dad.
What's up?
I'm struggling with
an ethical crisis.
Be a kid. Quit struggling.
Missy and I broke a lot
of rules the other night,
and we've received
no punishment.
[sighs]
Buddy, it's been a rough week.
We're just glad
you're both safe.
But in the absence
of a divine being,
society's rules are what keeps
a person's morality in check.
Well, there you go.
No, y-you're not
following me.
If actions have
no repercussions,
society breaks down,
everything devolves into chaos.
You might be overthinking this.
I thought so, too.
Then I thought about
it, and I'm not.
Sheldon, you had one bad night.
Just let it go.
But... I did something wrong
and I got away with it.
That's not okay.
Buddy...Socrates maintained
that the man
who lies to himself has
an enemy living within.
He's not even
a person.
He's just a chaos
of selfish desires
wrapped in an
animal hide.
Hey. Pastor
Jeff is here.
You up for some company?
You bet!
Got to talk to the pastor. Git.
Hey, George, Sheldon.
Excuse me, I have to "git."
Just wanted to bring by
some get-well cards
from the kids at Sunday school.
Well, isn't that sweet.
Some interesting spellings
of the name "George."
My favorites are
"Gorge" and "Garage."
[chuckles]:
Well, you tell the kids
that Coach Gorge appreciates it.
Will do.You want to sit?
I'm not gonna
stay long.
I just want to pray
over you a little
and let you get some rest.
Oh. Okay, yeah, sure.
Lord, I thank you
for George Cooper
and pray that
you heal him
from the inside out.
This is a good man,
a family man,
a devoted father
and a faithfulhusband.
Bless him and
everything he does.
Amen.
Heck yes, amen!
[knocking]
Hello.
Everything okay?
I'm having a moral quandary, and
I could really use your help.
Oh, moral quandaries.
I hate those.
Shoot.
You're the least moral person
I know--
how do you live with yourself?
I'm about to shut this door
in your face.
See? Other people would be kind
to a child in need.
That's why I came to you.
Okay, fine. What do you want?
I'm confused as to how
to go about my business
after misbehaving
and not being punished.
And where do I come in?You tell lies,
you gamble,
you have quite the potty mouth,
and yet you never seem to pay
a price for any of it.
Well, when you're cute like me,
rules are just
a little different.
Hmm. That would also explain
the endless parade
of romantic partners.
Are you leaving
because you have a man in there?
MEEMAW:
No!
Hmm. Although she would lie
about it, so who knows?
[knocking]Yeah?
Can I talk to you?
Of course. What's up?
I feel really bad
about the other day.
I was so mean to you.
Don't worry about it.
But you were just trying to help
and then I yelled at you
and then you had a heart attack.
[stammers]
That had nothing to do with you.
[crying]:
We don't know that.
Hey. Hey-hey.
Come here.
[sniffling]
[chuckles]
[sighs]I'm so sorry.
Shh.
[sniffles]
How are you doing
with all that... stuff?
You mean Marcus?
You don't have to talk about it
if you don't want to.
It's okay.
[sniffles]So, what happened?
You're not gonna
believe this,
but he was hanging out with
another girl behind my back.
Oh, well...
may-maybe they're
just friends.
Heather M. saw them holding
hands at the roller rink.
Does that sound like
friends to you?
Well... no.
[swallows]
Are all boys liars?
Uh... no.
I mean, how could
he do this to me?
I thought I could trust him.
Did he think
I wouldn't find out?
You know what, kiddo?
I think it's time for Daddy
to take his heart pills.
I'm glad we talked.
[chuckles]:
Oh, me, too, me, too.
Hey.
Hmm?I just wanted
to let you know
I invited Brenda over
for a big thank-you dinner.
[spits]
[chuckles]:
Oh. Terrific.
[sighs, coughs]
[door opens]
What are you doing?
Trying to fix this radio.
Should you be doing
that with a weak heart?
I'm just sitting here.
You look a little sweaty.
What do you want?
I'm gonna go hang
out with Jana.
Just wanted to make sure
you're doing okay.
Hold on.
Are you worried
I'm gonna have a heart attack
and interrupt "private time"
with your girlfriend?
Yes.
At least you're honest.
Glad you think so.
Bye.
See you.
BRENDA [whispers]:
Psst. George.
What's up?
How you doing?
Hanging in.So...
is it weird,
me coming over for dinner?
What do you mean?
You know exactly what I mean.
Brenda,
I had a lot to drink that night.
You know, I don't remember much.
You don't?
No, I do not.
Oh. Okay.
I guess I don't either.
Great. See you at dinner.
Yeah, mm-hmm.
SHELDON:
I still don't understand
why you'd rather work here
than be a physicist.
I'm enjoying the change of pace.
And they let me take home
all the expired food I want.
So, what brings
you here?Well, I did something wrong,
and yet I've received
no punishment.
What's my incentive
to behave morally
if the rules of society
aren't being enforced?
Reminds me of the Ring of Gyges.
I'm not familiar
with the Ring of Gyges.
Oh, it's
a delightful brainteaser.
Plato asked the question:
If you could wear a ring
that made you invisible,
what would prevent you
from committing
the most horrendous crimes?
Sounds an awful lot
like the Ring of Sauron
in The Lord of the Rings.
Oh. I'm not familiar
with The Lord of the Rings.
Oh, it's a delightful series
of fantasy books
in which there's a ring
that makes the wearer invisible
but also leads
to moral corruption.
Ooh. Perhaps you
should read Plato,
and I should read
The Lord of the Rings.
You should really start
with The Hobbit.
What's a hobbit?
It's a race of short humanoids
who live in burrows
and have hairy feet.
Oh. I've been called that.
But I never knew what it was.
MAN [on TV]:
The ancient secrets
of the mystic tarot
foreshadow your future.[phone ringing]
If you dare to discover
your destiny...
Hello?
Hey, Brenda.
WOMAN:
Your mind holds
limitless powers...
Oh, I'm so sorry
to hear that.
Well, we'll have to pick
another day, then.
Okay.
Feel better. Bye.
What's going on?
Brenda can't make it to dinner.
She's not feeling well.
Oh, that's too bad.I'll make hera plate
and run it over later.
I can bring that if you want.
You sure?
Yeah. I was a little out of it
at the hospital.
I really want to say thanks.
[door closes in distance]That'd be nice.
GEORGE JR.:
Ooh.
I'm in time for dinner. Good.
'Cause I have worked up
an appetite.
[knocking]
Hi.
Mary wanted to send over
some food,
since you weren't feeling well.
Thank you.
Can we talk a minute?
Look, I'm-I'm sorry
about earlier.
It's okay. I understand.
I just don't want this
to be weird.
We're neighbors.
You and my wife are friends.
Your kids aren't here, right?
No.
S-So, we're-we're neighbors.
You and my wife are friends.
That's why it's weird, George.
But nothing actually happened.
There's no reason
to feel guilty.
Okay.I mean,
did we have too much
to drink? Sure.
Did-did we talk about going home
from the bar together?
Okay, I'm sorry about that.No need to apologize,
'cause we didn't go.
All we did was have a nice time
in a public place. Mm?
Is there anything wrong
with that?
Kind of feels like it.
It does feel like it.
Why does it feel like it?[sighs]
Maybe...
...'cause it was nice to talk
to someone and feel special.
It was.
Mm, maybe you should go.
I should go.
Thanks for stopping by.Yeah.
Yeah, all right.
ADULT SHELDON: In the
face of a chaotic world,
we all seek comfort
in different ways.
Some turn to a higher power.Lord, please protect my family,
keep them in your hands.
All my cares, all my worries,
all my fears for them...
ADULT SHELDON:
Some take refuge
in fictitious worlds.
My congratulations,
Captain.
A dazzling display of logic.
You didn't think I had it in me,
did you, Spock?
No, sir.
["Learning to Fly"
by Tom Petty playing]
So great.
ADULT SHELDON:
And one person I know relied
on lighter fluid and a match.
♪ What goes up
That's right, burn.
♪ Must come down
What are you doing?!
Moving on.
♪ I'm learning to fly
♪ Learning to fly.♪From what?